

# Vikrant Milind Siddhartha <u> Electrical Quality Engineer(B.Tech)</u>



vikrant.ms2908@gmail.com vikrant.ms08@hotmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/vikrant-ms08

## **Objective:**

To work in Esteemed Organization so as to enhance my interpersonal Skills in conjunction with the company goals as well as my personal goals.

# Summary

I have 12+ year Experience in Power Distribution Projects and Operation & Maintenance of LT,HT networks and Power sub-stations as well as I have also worked in Railway tunnel Project for Electro-Mechanical work as an Quality Engineer and currently working in UP-RDSS Project as an Quality Engineer.

## **Experience Summary**

- 8 year Experienced in Power Distribution Projects.
- 3 year Experience of O&M Work in Distribution Franchise.
- 1.5 year Railway Tunnel Project(USBRL,J&K)(E&M Work)

# **Key Skills**

- Project Management.
- Power Distribution.
- Survey & Erection of T&D Network.
- Energy Meter Installation.
- Railway tunnel E&M Work.
- Material Inspection at Stores for Quality.
- Checks GTP's of Incoming Materials.
- Materials Testings at Stores.

# • Lab Testing of Materials with Clients.

- Man-Power Handelling.
- Minimize AT&C Losses.
- Contractor and Client Billings.
- Liasoning with Govt. Authorities.
- MS Office.

**Experience** 

#### MontecarloLimited.

Engineer(Quality Control)

Project:- UP-RDSS (AGRA Phase-2), DVVNL.

Feb 2024 - till date

- Coordination for Inspection & Performs Inspection and Lab testing with clients.
- Review of Quality Reports & Records & get it Approve from Clients.
- Site Visit for Inspection of On going Work.
- Inspect, Tests and Measure of Incoming Material at Store.
- Accept or Reject Finished item that fail to meet GTP.
- Detailed Planning and Scheduling of the Work in Progress.
- Quality Control through different routine tests.

### Ashoka Buildcon Limited.

Nov 2022 - Feb 2024

Quality Engineer.

Project:T-14 ANDT-15+T-40/41 DHARAM-KATRA SECTIONOF USBRL TUNNEL PROJECT E&M WORK Client:Ircon International Limited

- Assignment: Appointed as a Quality Engineer (EQA) to meticulously oversee the
  installation and commissioning of substations and associated equipment, while
  diligently managing contractors and ensuring strict compliance with technical
  specifications and approved materials on-site.
- Efficiently oversee E&M installations, ensuring compliance with technical specs, materials, and drawings.
- Verify equipment specifications and design systems for tunnel ventilation, firefighting, LT/HT, and lighting.
- Analyze electrical utility shifting estimates and optimize cable laying for LT and HT.
- Execute Earth Mat and Substation erection, emphasizing exothermic welding.
- · Lead tunnel and external earthing work with a focus on precision and safety.

# Vindhya Telelinks Limited(MP Birla Group)

Nov 2019-Aug 2021

Engineer

Project: IPDS Muzaffarpur, Bihar

- Managed IPDS Project under NBPDCL in Muzaffarpur, Bihar.
- Oversaw contractors, ensured material optimization, and provided daily progress reports.
- Prepared BOQ and JMC, generated MIS reports, and created SLDs.
- Installed 100KVA, 200KVA, and 315KVA transformers.
- Led erection and commissioning of 33KV and 11KV lines.
- Executed LT line conversions with AB Cables.
- Conducted quality inspections and resolved technical and public issues.
- Facilitated surveys and liaisoning with government authorities.

# Larson & Toubro(OFF Role)

<u>Aug 2018-Nov 2019</u>

Site Engineer

Project: 1-Saubhagya Scheme, Lakhimpur, Uttar Pradesh.

2-Replacement of bare conductor using ABC(Cable Conversion work).

- Site Inspection as a site Engineer for installation of Energy Meters.
- Prepared and Maintained the total Energy Meter, Erection, energization and store stock register
- village,block,sub Division,Division vise data.
- Responsible for Erection of BPL Energy Meters,LT Lines extention using AB cables,Erection of 11KV
- lines, Distribution Transformers.
- Handle the situation and resolve major/minor execution ROW's and restart the hampered execution work at site.
- Responsible to prepare daily progress reports.

## Aarvanss buildwell & Infracon LLP

Sep 2017-April 2018

Site Engineer

Project: DDUGJY Saharanpur, Uttar Pradesh

- Provided guidance to contractors to ensure work compliance.
- Managed effective material utilization.
- Presented daily progress reports to the project manager.
- Created Single Line Diagrams (SLDs) for pole-to-pole line measurement.
- Successfully installed Distribution transformers upto 315KVA.
- Led the erection and commissioning of 11KV lines.
- Executed LT line conversions using AB Cables.
- Conducted quality inspections.
- Provided weekly planning to contractors and resolved technical and public issues.
- Conducted surveys of 11KV and LT lines, marking for pole and transformer execution.
- Liaisoning with Government Authorities for project coordination.

# Essel Vityut Vitran Pvt Ltd(Essel Group)

April 2014-July 2017

Senior Executive

PROJECT-0&M work under Distribution Franchisee Ujjain City.

- Successfully oversaw the operation and maintenance of overhead electrical lines and distribution transformers.
- Responded to and resolved HT and LT breakdowns promptly and conducted patrolling of HT feeders to prevent feeder breakdowns.
- Managed teams to ensure the completion of projects within statutory timeframes and improved the existing network to reduce breakdowns.
- Coordinated with vendors for drawing and design approvals of LT and HT overhead lines, and prepared drawings for all HT and LT distribution network work.
- Made significant contributions to reducing Transmission and Distribution (T&D) losses.
- Played a pivotal role in electrification planning for previously unelectrified areas.

#### Medhaj techno concept Pvt Ltd Senior Engineer

Oct 2011-Dec 2013

#### PROJECT-Feeder seperation, Shivpuri, Madhya Pradesh

- Successfully finalized DPRs for feeder separation projects as part of the Government of India program.
- Conducted detailed studies of existing networks and load flow analysis for towns and regions.
- Performed network planning, including the calculation of load on 11KV lines and Distribution Transformers.
- Collaborated with electrical contractors throughout electrification, execution, erection, commissioning, and interfaced with government authorities.
- Monitored and supervised the erection of 11KV and LT lines and the installation of distribution transformers.

#### **Education**

- B. Tech (Electrical Engineering) | May 2010 Gautam Buddha Technical University | Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh
- (GATE Qualified in 2011)

#### **Computer Proficiency**

• Microsoft Office Suite: Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Good Computer knowledge.

#### **Additional Information**

• Languages: English,Hindi

## **Family Background**

- Father Name Vinod Kumar Siddhartha.
- Address 2587, Ramkunj colony Near Atri garden gate number-2 Sipri Bazar, Jhansi (Uttar Pradesh) PIN code-284003

#### **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned data are true, complete, and correct to the best of my Knowledge and belief.

Date-

Place-

Signature-

Reference-